(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-06T22:06:12.367318",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
痛くて目を塞いでも聞こえちゃう不安ショー
Even if I shut my eyes in pain, I still hear the anxiety show.
悩んでも変わらないからなんだかんだやるしかないか
Worrying won't change a thing, so I guess I've just gotta do it.
壊れるならいっそ直しやすいように
If it's gonna break, I'd rather make it easy to fix...
どんな形目指せるかな
...wondering what shape I can aim for.
助走なしのジャンプ 紐無しでダイブ
A jump without a running start, a dive without a rope.
今日のあたし褒めてあげたいじゃないか
Don't you think I should praise myself today?
息したいもっと響きたい
I wanna breathe, I wanna resonate more.
ねぇあたし以上が見えるかも 妄想止まんないや
Hey, maybe you'll see more than just me... My delusional thoughts won't stop!
ファッションビート 嗅いでみちゃう？
Fashion Beat! Wanna try taking a sniff?
夢にあっそなんて吐けやしないな
I can't just dismiss dreams with an "Oh, really?"
叶えるのはあたし自身か それとも誰かにお任せか
Will I fulfill them myself, or leave them to someone else?
ただただ自分に勝ちたい
I simply want to defeat myself!
ニューファッションビート 愛を喰らう
New Fashion Beat! Devouring love!
負けるなんてごめんだ 味もしないな
No way I'm losing, that leaves a bad taste in my mouth!
何度でも灰になる進化 生まれ変わるバグの擬人化
Evolving to turn into ashes again and again—a personification of a reborn bug.
まだまだ腐ってあげない そう、ない
I won't decay just yet—that's right, I won't!
チクチク刺してくるのは 飽き飽きしてるわ
I'm sick and tired of these prickling stabs.
ごめん 鬱陶しい言葉遊びは どうかちゃんと仕舞っておいて
Sorry, but please properly put away those annoying wordplays.
あたしこそがライバル 当たり前の解釈
I myself am my own rival—that's the obvious interpretation.
どうしたらいい分かってるのに
Even though I already know what I should do...
助走なしのジャンプ 紐無しでダイブ
A jump without a running start, a dive without a rope.
今日のあたし出来る気しないなって
Feeling like the present me can't pull it off today...
気にしないなんて無理じゃない？
Isn't it impossible to just ignore it?
ねぇあたし以外と比べても クソつまんないじゃないか うぜー
Hey, comparing me to anyone else is completely lame, isn't it? Annoying!
ファッションビート 嗅いでみちゃう？
Fashion Beat! Wanna try taking a sniff?
夢にあっそなんて吐けやしないな
I can't just dismiss dreams with an "Oh, really?"
叶えるのはあたし自身か それとも誰かにお任せか
Will I fulfill them myself, or leave them to someone else?
ただただ自分に勝ちたい
I simply want to defeat myself!
ニューファッションビート 愛を喰らう
New Fashion Beat! Devouring love!
負けるなんてごめんだ 味もしないな
No way I'm losing, that leaves a bad taste in my mouth!
何度でも灰になる進化 生まれ変わるバグの擬人化
Evolving to turn into ashes again and again—a personification of a reborn bug.
まだまだ腐ってあげない そう、ない 止まれない
I won't decay just yet—that's right, I won't! I can't be stopped!
Nya! Hello!! The beautiful days!!
刮目しちゃってくれ！
Keep your eyes wide open!
Please call 『Elite』!!
Please call me 『Elite』!!
(Funky dancin baby! ah)
(Ah!)
さぁ、待ったなしだ！始めっちゃえ！
Come on, no time to wait! Let's begin!
今日も引き締めて えいやで挑戦だ
Tighten up today too, and take on the challenge!
躊躇は厳禁 足踏みしてないで
Hesitation is forbidden, don't just mark time!
一緒に「せぇの！」でもっと前に行こうね？
Together, on "Ready, set...!", let's move forward!
さぁ、なんとか言っちゃえ！飛び込んで
Come on, say whatever and jump right in!
なんたってじっとしたっても人生は冒険だ
After all, even if you stay still, life is an adventure!
こんがらがったらまたわかんないぞ
If things get tangled up, you'll be lost again,
道のりは困難だ！
The path ahead is tough!
なんなんだ！上等だ！ダン・ダン・ダン！
What's that? Bring it on! Dan, dan, dan!
(あっはっ)
(Ah-ha)
メソメソしちゃって 気持ちに「待った」しちゃって
Whimpering around, putting a "hold" on your feelings,
あれ？一体全体どうしたん？
Huh? What on earth happened?
絶体絶命！？
A desperate crisis!?
君たちには
For you guys...
涙は似合わないね！
tears just don't suit you!
大大大大冒険に飛び出そうぜ！
Let's jump right out into a big adventure!
(良いじゃんねぇ！)
(Isn't that great?)
大大大大失敗も重ねて成長して
Piling up big failures to grow,
Happyな feel soで
With a happy feeling,
君と笑い話にしよう
let's turn it into a story to laugh about!
(つまり)
(In short)
大大大大問題も吹き飛ばせ！
Blow away even big, big problems!
いつか大大大大団円の素敵な結末へ
Someday towards a wonderful, happy ending!
Please me!! さぁ、付いてきて？
Please me!! Come on, follow me, okay?
進め！前代未聞の New world!
Advance! To an unprecedented new world!
(Let's go!!)
あながち間違ってる ま～た墓穴も掘ってる
You're wrong, digging your own grave again~
勉強！勉強！
Learning! Learning!
(はいはいはい、知ってます。待って、なんか違ってる！)
(Yeah yeah, I know. Wait, something's wrong!)
ぶっちゃけ有識者の皆様に感謝してます！
To be honest, I'm grateful to all the experts!
Nice comment's 待ってんぜ
I'm waiting for nice comments!
(あ～ね)
(Ah, I see)
ウジウジしちゃって 心にロックしちゃって
Hesitating and locking up your heart,
ほら、だんだんだんだんダウンしちゃ
Look, feeling down bit by bit...
絶体絶命！？
A desperate crisis!?
君たちには
For you guys...
笑顔が足りてないね！
you don't have enough smiles!
大大大大大好きじゃ収まらない！
Just loving it isn't enough!
(良いじゃんねぇ！)
(Isn't that great?)
大大大大満足のその上の感動を！
Beyond satisfaction, give us greater emotion!
もっと欲しがっちゃって？
Craving for even more?
豪快に贅沢に行こう
Let's go magnificently and luxuriously!
(つまり)
(In short)
全然前進しないなって凹んじゃったって
Even if you feel down with no progress at all,
ならば全身全霊エンジン全開
Then go all-out with full spirit and throttle!
本気の全力で
With serious, maximum effort!
Nya! Hello!! さぁ beautifulに！
Nya! Hello!! Come on, beautifully!
意気込んで進め！ Freedom way!
Press forward with determination! Freedom way!
(wow wow)
乗り遅れんなよみんな！
Don't miss the ride, everyone!
(wow wow)
声を聞かせてくれ！ Yeah!
Let me hear your voices! Yeah!
(wow wow)
歌おう声高らかに
Let's sing out loud and clear!
(wow wow)
ベイベー ベイベー
Baby, baby...
なんていうか…
How should I put it...
あぁ、なんだかちょっと言い表せない
Ah, somehow I can't quite put it into words...
一人ぼっちで見てた光景を
The scenery I used to watch all by myself,
今はきっとあなたと冒険してる！
now I'm surely exploring it together with you!
大大大大大大大大大大好きじゃ収まらない！
Just loving it so much can't hold it all!
(だから)
(So)
最大最高レベルにガチの全力で！
At the highest level, with genuine full effort!
Nya! Hello!! 届いちゃうぜ！
Nya! Hello!! We'll reach it!
ずっと大冒険しよう Yeah!!
Let me go on a grand adventure forever, Yeah!!
大大大大問題も吹き飛ばせ！
Blow away even big, big problems!
いつか大大大大団円の素敵な結末へ
Someday towards a wonderful, happy ending!
Please me!! さぁ、付いてきて？
Please me!! Come on, follow me, okay?
進め！前代未聞の New world!
Advance! To an unprecedented new world!
刮目しちゃってくれ！
Keep your eyes wide open!
Please call 『Elite』!!
Please call me 『Elite』!!
(Funky dancin baby! ah)
(Ah!)
「とくべちゅ、して？」
"Give me a special kiss, okay?"
Oh baby 「I love you」 じゃ足りない
Oh baby, "I love you" isn't enough,
一番大事がいい
I want to be your most important one.
君が作るオリジナルの
Give me an original...
特別、チューして。
special kiss created by you.
眩しくて目が覚めて
Dazzled by the light, I open my eyes,
Oh yeah!
愛おしく思ってよ
Please hold me dear,
Oh yeah!
眠り姫のように
Like Sleeping Beauty,
優しく口付けて
Kiss me ever so gently.
ゴミめいた この世界
In this world full of trash,
Oh yeah!
ピュアがかかる 君がいる
There's you, shining with purity.
Oh yeah!
全てに触れずに
Without touching anything else,
2人だけでいよう
Let's stay just the two of us.
私のこと 独占して
Keep me all to yourself,
君だけのモノになってもいい
I wouldn't mind becoming yours alone.
なん原理もある日の 「なんでもない」
On an ordinary day, notice my "it's nothing,"
気付いてね
Please notice it, okay?
Oh baby 「I love you」 じゃ足りない
Oh baby, "I love you" isn't enough,
君の「特別」にして
Make me your "special someone."
ねぇ もっと Give me a kiss
Hey, give me a kiss, even more!
もう私は 君でいっぱいよ
I'm already so completely full of you.
ほどけない リボン結び
Tie an unbreakable ribbon,
小指キュッて縛って
Bind our pinkies tightly together.
そうよ 一生一緒がいいもん
That's right, I want to be together forever.
とくべチュが欲しい
I want a special kiss.
2人きり週末は
On weekends with just the two of us,
Oh yeah!
奏でてよ ハーモニー
Play our harmony,
Oh yeah!
流れ星見たら
If you see a shooting star,
私を想ってほしい
I want you to think of me.
あまあまな君なのに
You're usually so sweet and gentle,
Oh yeah!
広い街 吸い込まれ
But swallowed by the big city,
Oh yeah!
戦う姿に
Seeing you work so hard,
大きいはなまるだね
Deserves a big gold star!
好きなところ、優しいとこ。
What I like about you is how gentle you are.
嫌いなとこも、優しいとこ。
What I dislike is also how gentle you are.
誰にもあげない
I won't give you to anyone else,
私だけ 独り占め！
I'm keeping you all to myself!
う～だって 今までの人と
Ugh, because I don't want someone
同じはいらないんです
Who's just like everybody else.
ねぇ もっと Give me more love
Hey, give me more love,
私のため 生きてほしいんです
I want you to live for my sake.
だから ウサギと私は 寂しくさせないで
So don't make rabbits or me feel lonely.
そんなんじゃ 束縛じゃないわ
Something like that isn't clingy at all,
苦しいのが好き
I like being tied down!
ショートケーキ イチゴみたいに 座ってもいい？
Can I sit on top like a strawberry on a shortcake?
赤く甘い恋だもん
Because this is a red, sweet love!
誰かにあげた 「大好き」 も
Even the "I love you"s you gave to others,
返してもらって 全部私に
Take them back and give them all to me!
Yeah!
ちょーだい、、もっと！
Give them to me... more!
君は神様が作る
You are a miracle person
奇跡のようなヒト
Created by God.
拗ねた顔も その寝顔も
Your pouting face and your sleeping face,
守ってあげるね
I'll protect them all.
Yeah!
Oh baby 「I love you」 じゃ足りない
Oh baby, "I love you" isn't enough,
君の「特別」にして
Make me your "special someone."
ねぇ もっと Give me a kiss
Hey, give me a kiss, even more!
もう私は 君でいっぱいよ
I'm already so completely full of you.
ほどけない リボン結び
Tie an unbreakable ribbon,
小指キュッて縛って
Bind our pinkies tightly together.
ねぇ baby 最初で最後の とくべチュにしてね
Hey baby, make it my first and last special kiss, okay?
はい！みんな～！にゃはろ～！
Okay! Everyone~! Nyaharo~!
エリート巫女アイドルのさくらみこ～！
I'm elite miko idol, Sakura Miko~!
さくらみこ生誕祭2026『Fashion Beat』に来てくれて、どうもありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to Sakura Miko Birthday Live 2026 "Fashion Beat"!
今年でなんとみこちゃん 18.8歳になりましたー！ 多分18.8歳だよね？
This year, Miko-chan turned 18.8 years old! It's probably 18.8 years old, right?
はい、0.1でね、刻んでいく系のVTuberですから！今年も18.8歳になりましたー！
Yeah, I'm the type of VTuber who ages by 0.1 increments! So I turned 18.8 years old this year too!
そしてそして、今回のライブのテーマは『Fashion Beat』にちなんでですね、ファッションとなっております！
And also, themed after "Fashion Beat," the theme of this live concert is fashion!
いろんなね、演出が盛りだくさんなので、ぜひ楽しんでください！
There are tons of different special stage performances, so please enjoy!
じゃあね、ちょっとまぁファッションにちなんで、みこちゃんもちょっとだけチェンジしちゃおうかな～？
So, sticking with the fashion theme, maybe Miko-chan should change her look just a little bit too~?
はい、上向いててくださーい！よいしょ...
Okay, please look up! Up we go...
はい！じゃーん！
Here we go! Ta-da!
ということで、クリスマスのね、ライブではね...
So, at the Christmas live concert...
...をしなかった こちらの...
...did not wear. This one...
キャストオフバージョンになっております
...is the cast-off version!
こんな感じになってます 可愛いでしょう？
It looks like this! Isn't it cute?
ちょっとセクシーですけどね
It's a little bit sexy, though!
はい！
Yes!
可愛い〜！
Cute~!
はい 次の曲はこれで披露しようと思っておりました
Yes, I was thinking of performing the next song in this outfit!
そして先ほどね 2曲お届けしましたがどうでしたか？
And how were the two songs we performed earlier?
みこのオリ曲の『ラライライファンタジスタ』と
Miko's original song "Lalalai Fantasista"...
そしてみこのね 大好きなアイドルさんの特別出演をしていただきました！
...and a special performance with Miko's favorite idol!
とっても可愛かったでしょう？
Wasn't it super cute?
きゅんきゅん きゅんきゅん はい！
So adorable! Yes!
あ そうだ ステージもね ちょっと見せたいんですけど
Oh, that's right! I also want to show you the stage set!
見てください！
Please take a look!
こちら 今回のテーマにちなんで作っていただきました！
They made this based on today's theme!
ドレッサーとかね めちゃくちゃね
The vanity dresser and everything are so huge...
みこが小人になったみたいな感じですけど
...it feels like Miko became tiny!
ね とっても可愛くなっております
Right? It turned out super cute!
そしてこちらのね トルソーね
And over here, on these mannequins...
みこちゃんの歴代の衣装とかも少し飾ってあります
...some of Miko's past outfits are on display!
全部じゃないんですけどね
Not all of them, though!
はい！
Yes!
えー そして
And also...
最後にですね たくさんの告知があったりとか
At the end, we have lots of announcements...
新衣装のお披露目もございますので！
...and a new outfit reveal as well!
ぜひ楽しんでもらえたらなと思っております！
So I really hope you all enjoy it until the end!
では！
Now then!
早速ゲストパート行こうと思いますよ！
Let's jump right into the guest segment!
よし こうして
Alright, moving over...
それではこの後も楽しんでね！
Keep having fun for the rest of the stream!
よし！
Alright!
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster!
おもしろいって言いたいのに
I want to say that it's interesting,
言えないなんてつまらないでしょ
so isn't it boring not to be able to say it?
おなじになっていい子でなんて
I don't wanna be the same and be a good girl,
いたくないってキミもそうでしょ
and I'm sure you feel the same way too!
だれかのルールに縛られたくはないの
I don't want to be bound by anyone else's rules.
わがままドキドキこのままでいたい
Selfish, heart pounding, I want to stay as I am!
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster!
この狭い心の檻もこわして自由になりたいの
I want to break the narrow cage of my heart and be free!
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster!
感覚をとぎすませてキミのように
Sharpening up my senses, just like you,
すいこまれてく螺旋模様みたいに
sucked in like a spiral pattern,
I wanna be free
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster!
ただふつうに生きたいのに
I just want to live normally,
へんなことってつまらないでしょ
so calling it weird is just boring, right?
きめつけないでいい子でなんて
Don't judge me, I don't wanna be a good girl,
いたくないってキミもそうでしょ
and I'm sure you feel the same way too!
だれかの
Someone's...
ルールに
Tied down by rules...
縛られたくはないの
I don't wanna be tied down.
わがまま ドキドキ このままでいたい
Selfish, heart pounding, I wanna stay like this.
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
鉄の首飾りをはずして
Take off the iron necklace
ただ自由に生きたいだけ
I just wanna live freely.
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
この狭い心の檻も 壊して自由になりたいの
I want to break the narrow cage of my heart and be free.
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
咲き誇れ花よ 舞い踊れ
Bloom in full glory, flowers! Dance away!
明日を虹色に染め上げて
Dye tomorrow in rainbow colors!
いくぞー！
Here we go!
ソイヤ！
Soiya!
はーどっこい はっじまるぞー！
Here we go, starting now!
今から歌うは ウルトラ スーパー いtoiとおかしの 夢色リズムさ
What we're about to sing is an ultra super, deeply charming dream-colored rhythm!
「おかし」な故にね 心惹かれるの まぁそんな噂はどうでもいいのさ
Because it's "strange", it captivates the heart! Well, such rumors don't matter at all!
大事なのは 楽しむ心 準備はいいかな？ 遅れないでよね
What matters most is a joyful heart! Are you ready? Don't fall behind!
あ！ 囃子輝く街に 靴紐結んで 3, 2, 1で飛び出せ！
Ah! Tie your shoelaces in the glowing festival city, and leap out on 3, 2, 1!
ワクワクしたいの！ ドキドキしたくない！？ ウキウキさせてよ！ もういい？
I wanna be excited! Don't you wanna feel your heart thumping?! Get me thrilled! Is that enough?
いやいやまだまだ なんていうか止まらない！ なんていうか止まれない！
No, no, not yet! Somehow it won't stop! Somehow we can't stop!
まだまだ明日の景色を見ていたくない？
Don't you want to keep looking at tomorrow's scenery?
それ！ よイしょ！ はい！
There! Heave-ho! Yeah!
咲き誇れ！ 君も ヨイサ！ヨイサ！ だからここは 最高のフェスティバル
Bloom in full glory! You too, Yoisa! Yoisa! So this place is the greatest festival!
祭囃子リズムで ノリノリさ 笑顔満開→無限大 It's Alright!
Grooving to the festival rhythm, smiles in full bloom -> infinite! It's alright!
舞い踊れ！ ひぃふぅみぃで染め上げて 君色教えて 気になっちゃう color
Dance away! Dye it all in 1, 2, 3! Show me your color, a color I'm so curious about!
そんな感じで 良いさ！良いさ！ 夢のビート聴かせてよ
Just like that, it's great! It's great! Let me hear the dream's beat!
ソイヤ！
Soiya!
はーどっこい
Haa dokkoi!
どっこいしょーどっこいしょ
Dokkoisho, dokkoisho!
続けて歌うは ウルトラ スーパー いtoiとおかしの 夢色リズムさ
Continuing to sing an ultra super, deeply charming dream-colored rhythm!
もしかしましても さっきも言ったっけ？ まぁそんな話はどうでもいいのさ
Could it be that I already said this earlier? Well, such talk doesn't matter at all!
大事なのは 信じる心 君だけ聞こえる リズムに任せて
What matters most is a believing heart! Leave it to the rhythm that only you can hear!
あ！ 星空きらめく街を もっともっと照らすくらい 3, 2, 1で飛び出せ！
Ah! Bright enough to illuminate the starry-glowing city even more, leap out on 3, 2, 1!
ワクワクしたいの！ ドキドキしたくない！？ ウキウキさせてよ！ もういい？
I wanna be excited! Don't you wanna feel your heart thumping?! Get me thrilled! Is that enough?
いやいやまだまだ なんていうか終わらない？ なんていうか止まれない！
No, no, not yet! Somehow won't it end? Somehow we can't stop!
今宵も夢色を抱きしめて
Embracing the dream color tonight as well...
いっくぞー！
Here we go!
咲き誇れ！ 君も ソイヤ！ソイヤ！ だからここは 最高のフェスティバル
Bloom in full glory! You too, Soiya! Soiya! So this place is the greatest festival!
曖昧なリズムに ドキドキさ 空に満開→無限大 It's Alright! 舞い上がれ！ ひぃふぅみぃで染め上げて 君色教えて 内緒にする color
Thrilled by the ambiguous rhythm! Full bloom in the sky -> infinite! It's alright! Soar high! Dye it all in 1, 2, 3! Show me your color, a secret color...
あーそんな感じで
Ah, in that style!
あん！ あん！
Ah, 1 2 3!
夢のビートきざもうよ
Let's engrave the beat of our dreams!
さわげー！ 咲き誇れ
Make some noise! Bloom in full glory!
さよい さよい だから
Here we go, here we go, so...
最高のフェスティバル
It's the ultimate festival!
祭リズムで ノリノリ
Riding high on the festival rhythm!
笑顔満開 無限大 It's Alright!
Smiles in full bloom to infinity! It's alright!
ひいふうみいて 跳ねあげて
Count 1, 2, 3 and jump up!
君色教えて 気になっちゃう color
Tell me your color, I'm so curious about your color!
そんな感じで あん！ あん！
Just like that! An! An!
夢のビート聴かせてよ
Let me hear the beat of your dreams!
だから止まれない！
So we can't stop now!
はっ！ はっ！
Ha! Ha!
ソイヤ！ ソイヤ！ ソイヤ！
Soiya! Soiya! Soiya!
はーどっこい！
Ha, dokkoi!
どっこいしょ どっこいしょ！
Dokkoisho, dokkoisho!
ぶつけたところから
From where we collided,
熟れていく果実のように
like a fruit slowly ripening,
僕らは些細なことで へこたれたよな
we used to get discouraged over the smallest things, didn't we?
かさぶたになれずに
Unable to even form a scab,
息せき切って がむしゃらに
gasping for breath, recklessly,
輝く一等星をめがけて
aiming for that shining first-magnitude star,
手を伸ばしたよな
we reached out our hands, didn't we?
繊細されど大胆だ
Delicate, yet bold!
うるさい これが切り札だ
Shut up, this is our trump card!
泣き虫されど熱血だ
A crybaby, yet passionate!
うるさい これが持ち味だ
Shut up, this is our special trait!
未開拓冒険地帯 ∴ 好奇心旺盛時代
Unexplored adventure zones, an age of endless curiosity!
何が綺麗かは分かる 見る目ならばある
We know what's beautiful; we have the eye for it.
恥ずかしいか青春は
Is youth something to be ashamed of?
馬鹿らしいか真剣は
Is taking things seriously something foolish?
僕ら全力でやってんだ
We're giving it everything we've got!
振りかざせ存在を 掻き乱せ心臓を
Flaunt your existence! Stir up your beating heart!
あとどれくらい 続いていくだろう
How much longer will this continue?
守り抜いた青春が
The youth we've protected to the end...
何よりも贅沢だ
is the greatest luxury of all!
きっといつか 焦がれ思い返す
Surely, someday we'll look back on it with longing.
名前のない関係を 捨てる気ない感情を
These nameless bonds, these feelings we can't throw away...
何気ない今日を 忘れないでね
Please don't ever forget this casual today.
悩んでた種の色が
The color of the seed we worried over...
昨日とはまるで違うとか
being completely different from yesterday,
そんなの日常茶飯事だね
that's just an everyday occurrence, isn't it?
心は素直のようだ
It seems our hearts are honest after all.
戦友だとか親友は うるさいどれも正解だ
"Comrades-in-arms" or "best friends"—shut up, every answer is right!
初恋だとか失恋は うるさいどれも宝石だ
"First love" or "heartbreak"—shut up, every single one is a gem!
天才的 人生企画
A genius life plan,
問題集 対抗美学
A problem collection, counter-aesthetics
君はなにしてんのかな
I wonder what you're doing
話がしたい
I want to talk to you
風に乗って青春が
Riding on the wind, youth
この想いを運んだ
Has carried these feelings
僕ら全力を超えたいんだ
We want to go beyond our full power
立ちすくむ同士だって
Even those standing frozen,
引き連れていこうぜ
Let's bring them along with us
この上ない今日を過ごしていたいよ
I want to spend this best of all days
今しかできない事がある
There are things that can only be done now
今しかできない恋がある
There's a love that can only happen now
今しかできないから
Because we can only do it now,
僕らに託された時間が惜しい
The time entrusted to us is precious
今しか見られない 君の笑顔も 君の涙も
Your smile and your tears that can only be seen now,
君の全てにも
And everything about you,
大人びていく
Are growing up
有限だから最高だ
It's the best because it's finite
恥ずかしいか青春は
Is youth embarrassing?
馬鹿らしいか真剣は
Is being serious foolish?
僕ら全力でやってんだ
We're giving it everything we've got
振りかざせ存在を
Brandish your existence
掻き乱せ心臓を
Stir up your heart
胸に刻めば続いていくだろう
If you engrave it in your heart, it will carry on
守り抜いた青春が
The youth we've protected through and through
何よりも贅沢だ
Is the greatest luxury of all
きっといつか焦がれ思い返す
Someday we'll surely yearn for and look back on
名前のない関係を
A relationship without a name,
捨てきれない感情を
Feelings we can't completely let go of
何気ない今日を忘れないでね
Don't forget this ordinary today, okay?
この上ない今日を忘れないでね
Don't forget this incomparable today, okay?
ア... アイドルだから
Ah... because I'm an idol,
挑み続けるんだ 君と夢見るんだ
I'll keep challenging, dreaming together with you
不器用で悪いか
Is it so wrong to be clumsy?
咲き誇るよ
I will bloom in full glory
初のイベント 需要無しデフォルト
First event, default with zero demand
そんな私がい夢を見ました
Someone like me had a dream
アイドルという生き方 憧れて
Longing for the way of life as an idol
「無敵エリート」「笑顔はチート」
"Invincible Elite," "Cheater Smile"
こんな私を見てくれる君
You, who watch someone like me
好きなとこはどこですか？
What is it about me that you like?
わがままを許して
Forgive my selfishness
ステージ経験値 涙滲んで
Stage experience blurred with tears
それでも絶対負けたくない
Even so, I definitely don't want to lose
桜にメッセージ乗せて届け
Send a message riding on cherry blossoms
愛で溢れますように
May it overflow with love
ア... アイドルだから
Ah... because I'm an idol,
挑み続けるんだ 君と夢見るんだ
I'll keep challenging, dreaming together with you
不器用で悪いか 咲き誇れ
Is it wrong to be clumsy? Bloom in full glory!
妄想だけじゃ終わらせない
I won't let it end as just a fantasy
私らしく 桜色ね
True to myself, cherry blossom pink, right?
磨いたスキル 実力発揮
Polished skills, demonstrating my true ability
楽しめる日も増えてきたんだ
The days I can enjoy have been increasing
アイドルとして生きてる 君のおかげ
Living as an idol, all thanks to you
アホ毛はキュート！勝ち確ルート！
Cowlick is cute! Guaranteed victory route!
そんな私についてきてよね！
Follow someone like me, okay?
ドジなとこも許されて
Even my clumsy side gets forgiven
最強ジャン！
Isn't that the strongest?
痛いの言いたいのグッと飲み込んで
Gulping down the painful things I want to say
笑顔で笑顔増やしたいな
I want to bring more smiles with a smile
桜前線が君の町に
May the cherry blossom front reach your town
春を届けるように
To deliver spring to you
ア... アイドルだけは
Ah... as for being an idol,
譲りたくないんだ 君に見せたいんだ
I don't want to yield it; I want to show you
理想へ挑むよ 駆け抜けろ
Challenging my ideals, run through!
最高景色見せてあげる
I'll show you the best scenery
信じていいよ 桜を
It's okay to believe in Sakura
さぁ皆で咲かそう
Come on, let's bloom together!
満開のピンクで世界染めて
Dyeing the world in full-bloom pink
あぁこの涙はね
Ah, these tears, you know...
Ah, these tears of mine, you see,
悲しい方じゃないから
aren't from sadness.
安心して
So don't you worry.
きれいだね
It's so beautiful.
今年も誕生日お祝いしてくれてありがとー！
Thank you for celebrating my birthday with me again this year!
みんなー！大好きだよー！
Everyone! I love you all so much!
ア・イ・ド・ル アイドルだから
I'm an i-d-o-l, because I'm an idol!
挑み続けるんだ
I'll keep taking on challenges.
君と夢見るんだ
Dreaming together with you.
不器用で悪いか
Is it so wrong to be clumsy?
咲き誇れ
Bloom in full glory!
妄想だけじゃ終わらせない
I won't let it end as just a fantasy.
私らしく
True to myself...
桜色ね♡
In cherry blossom pink ♡
みんなー！ありがとー！
Everyone! Thank you so much!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
ありがとねー！
Thank you all!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
お祝いしてくれてありがとねー！楽しんでるー？
Thank you for celebrating with me! Are you having fun?
ありがとー！
Thank you!
ありがとー！んーっ、まっ！
Thank you! *mwah!*
見てるよー！みんな見てるよー！
I see you! I see all of you!
よーし！ということで！ライブ、まだまだ盛り上がる準備できてますかー？！
All right! With that said, are you ready to get even more hyped for the concert?!
みんなー！まだまだみんな逃げないでねー！
Everyone! Don't run away just yet, okay?!
よーし、次の曲いきます！
All right, moving on to the next song!
Now I'm ready, I'm ready to go
花が咲く時が来たんだ
The time has come for the flower to bloom.
Are you ready? わかるでしょ
Are you ready? You already know, don't you?
やってみせる Make it through
I'll show you I can make it through!
ほら ほら ほら
Look, look, look!
ゾワゾワしてきた
I'm getting goosebumps!
時は過ぎちゃうから 今すぐに
Time is passing by, so right now,
Let's work it out
もう 目を背けやしないんだ
I won't look away anymore.
自分で M@KE IT★BETTER
Making it better myself!
正解を作る
Creating my own correct answer.
I just wanna, just wanna find somebody
私よりも強気な
Someone even bolder than me,
ダーーWHOーレーーWHOーカ
Who, who, who could it be?
Make You Hot Make You Hot 準備体操 お済みですか？
Make You Hot, Make You Hot! Done with your warm-up exercises?
この勝負 Victory
This showdown, Victory!
SO LET'S NOW START THE WAR!
I'm fighting my way I'm fighting my way
夢の未来図 信じて進むだけ
Believing in the blueprint of my dream, I just move forward!
誰にも絶対 負ける気なんかナイ
There's no way I'll lose to anyone!
君に見せたいの 彼方の景色を！
I want to show you the scenery beyond!
恋に踊れ 情熱全て
Dance in love, with all your passion!
もっと先を知りたい もう止まらない
I want to know what's further ahead, I can't stop anymore!
Ay-ay Ay-ay Ay-ay
I WILL LEAD THE WAY... JUST COME ALONG MY WAY
Hey! Don't kill my vibe 行こう 一番上まで
Hey! Don't kill my vibe, let me go all the way to the top!
ちょっと待ってよなんか 誤解な振る舞っちゃってない？ねぇ
Wait a second, am I acting a bit misunderstood? Hey,
蹴落とすため戦うわけではないの
I'm not fighting to kick others down.
JUST WANNA KEEP CHALLENGING MYSELF
Huh? こんなFANTASY ハマったら
Huh? If you fall for a fantasy like this,
MORE MORE 欲しくなっちゃうよ
you'll end up wanting MORE, MORE!
もう 何も恐れはしないんだ
I'm not afraid of anything anymore!
君となら 行ける気がするから
Because with you, I feel like I can go anywhere!
Come join us ほら 聞こえて来るから
Come join us! Look, you can hear it coming,
Yea 私の名を呼ぶ声
Yea, the voices calling my name!
I'm fighting my way I'm fighting my way
夢の未来図 信じて進むだけ
Believing in the blueprint of my dream, I just move forward!
誰にも絶対 負ける気なんかナイ
There's no way I'll lose to anyone!
君に見せたいの 彼方の景色を！
I want to show you the scenery beyond!
運命だって 夜を抜け 雨を受け
Even with fate, breaking through the night, braving the rain,
青空の光 求めた
seeking the light of the blue sky!
Whoa
一つも無駄はないさ
Not a single thing is in vain.
パワーに変えて
Turning it into power,
輝いてくから
because I will keep on shining!
KIRA KIRA 弾けた
Sparkling and bursting with light,
Ah 神の思召しだ
Ah, it's God's divine will!
連れてくよ Make you high
I'll take you there, Make you high!
後悔はさせない 超えるんだ Borderless
I won't let you regret it, crossing over, Borderless!
SO LET'S NOW START THE WAR!
I'm fighting with myself I'm fighting with myself
負けなんてナイ 勝負受けて立つだけ
There's no defeat! I just stand and accept the challenge!
もう自分自身 私に勝てナイ
Even my former self can't beat me now!
君がいれば 何度も立ち上がるわ！
As long as you're here, I'll rise up again and again!
愛を歌え 思い全て
Sing of love with all your feelings!
逃げたくはない
I don't wanna run away,
待てない
I can't wait,
まだ終われない
It can't end yet,
I NEED YOU TODAY
YOU MAKE ME FEEL OKAY HEY!
It's time to shine!
行こう 空の上まで
Let's go, up to the sky!
Wah ah wah oh
Pam pam pam para pam pam pam
Ahhh uh ah ooh
唸るぜ
I'm gonna roar,
血泥ついたって
even covered in blood and mud,
守りたい
I want to protect you.
革命道中だって
Even in the midst of revolution,
君に夢中
I'm crazy about you.
暗闇染み込む世界で
In a world soaked in darkness,
見つけた
I found
センチメンタルな恋
a sentimental love.
甘くぬかるんだ眼差し
A sweet, muddy gaze,
変に色気あるから困った
troubled by your strangely alluring charm.
手を繋ぐ勇気出したくて
Wanting to summon the courage to hold hands,
身の程わきまえてちゃできないね
you can't do it if you know your place.
暗いトンネルの先へ
Toward the end of the dark tunnel,
しずやかに高鳴る心
my heart quietly throbs with excitement.
ダメダメ
No, no,
待て待て
wait, wait,
呪いも病みも
curses and sickness alike,
抱きしめたい ここらで暴れちゃってもいいかな
I wanna embrace them. Is it okay if I go wild around here?
あー唸るぜ
Ah, I'm gonna roar,
血泥ついたって 守りたい
even covered in blood and mud, I want to protect you.
革命道中だって
Even in the midst of revolution,
君に夢中
I'm crazy about you.
暗闇染み込む世界で
In a world soaked in darkness,
見つけた
I found
センチメンタルな恋
a sentimental love.
なりふり構わず側にいたい
Regardless of appearances, I want to be by your side.
不器用な君にも期待しちゃうよ
I can't help expecting things from clumsy you.
しがみつけば消えそうな君に
To you who seem like you'd vanish if I clung to you,
恋の爪立てて近づいてもいい？
can I dig in the claws of love and draw near?
身を任せて抱かれて全て失ってもいい
I don't mind surrendering, being held, and losing everything.
しずやかに高鳴る心
My heart quietly throbs with excitement.
ダメダメ
No, no,
待て待て
wait, wait,
呪いも病みも
curses and sickness alike,
抱きしめたい ここらで暴れちゃってもいいかな
I wanna embrace them. Is it okay if I go wild around here?
あー泣けるぜ
Ah, it brings tears to my eyes,
絶句しちゃうまで
until I'm completely speechless,
離れない
I won't leave.
革命道中だって
Even in the midst of revolution,
君に夢中
I'm crazy about you.
揺蕩う旅の狭間で
Found in the midst of a wavering journey,
見つけた
I found
センチメンタルな恋
a sentimental love.
突き進むなら二人で
If we push forward, let's do it together.
革命道中だって夢に熱中
Even in the midst of revolution, absorbed in our dream.
ダメダメ
No, no,
待て待て
wait, wait,
呪いも病みも
curses and sickness alike,
抱きしめたい ここらで暴れちゃってもいいよね
I wanna embrace them. Is it okay if I go wild around here?
怖くたって
Even if I'm scared,
唸るぜ 血泥ついたって
I'll roar, even covered in blood and mud,
守りたい
I want to protect you.
革命道中だって
Even in the midst of revolution,
君に夢中
I'm crazy about you.
暗闇染み込む世界で
In a world soaked in darkness,
見つけた
I found
センチメンタルな恋
a sentimental love.
飛べ 起こせ！
Fly, make a move!
願うは事故
All I want is trouble
一世一代
Only one chance,
さあ何賭す？
what do you bet on?
自問自答
Answer yourself
勝つか 負けるか
It's about victory or defeat,
ドローなんてないわ
there can't be a draw.
ah, ah, ah, hey
幕開けるわ
Let's open the curtains
カッチンして ラッキーマネー どっちも無理 シガー シガー
Get ticked off, lucky money, both are impossible, cigar, cigar
引けるか 否か 自分次第 居ただな 余裕で
Whether you can pull it off or not is up to you. It's easy, right?
振り切りで BET だぜ イエイイエイイエイイエイ
Going all in with a max BET, yeah yeah yeah yeah
そこの彼 そこのエイブ かっさらうのは アタシだ
Hey you over there, hey handsome, I'm the one taking it all!
Stay もういい 勝ったなら 平常心
Stay, that's enough, if you won, stay cool
ねぇプレイボーイ 行け Don't get in my way じゃあね 黙って
Hey playboy, go away, don't get in my way. Bye now, quiet down
ワン ツー スリー ワン ツー スリー ワン ツー スリー
One, two, three, one, two, three, one, two, three
Sit down Sit down ワン ツー スリー ワン ツー スリー ワン ツー スリー
Sit down, sit down. One, two, three, one, two, three, one, two, three
はーもうフリーズ決めて
Hah, locking it down into a freeze...
投げ出すのうっそサイクっさ
giving up? No way, that's so tacky!
そんな小さい指示じゃ動けない
I can't move on such tiny instructions!
でしょう そうでしょう セイ・グッバイ
Right? That's right, say goodbye
あっち こっち そっち どっち？ nothing nothing
Over there, over here, that way, which way? Nothing, nothing
道なき道を イエイイエイイエイ
A pathless path, yeah yeah yeah
空回りしそう でもまだ止めないで
Spinning my wheels, but don't stop me yet
あーもうそれそう 声々 それそれ Get out the way
Ah, that's right, make some noise, get out of the way
アンタはここまで 後ろだけ見とけ
This is as far as you go. Just watch my back
カッチンして ラッキーマネー どっちも無理 シガー シガー
Get ticked off, lucky money, both are impossible, cigar, cigar
引けるか 否か 自分次第 居ただな 余裕で
Whether you can pull it off or not is up to you. It's easy, right?
振り切りで BET だぜ イエイイエイイエイイエイ
Going all in with a max BET, yeah yeah yeah yeah
そこの彼 そこのエイブ かっさらうのは アタシだ
Hey you over there, hey handsome, I'm the one taking it all!
Stay もういい 勝ったなら 平常心
Stay, that's enough, if you won, stay cool
ねぇプレイボーイ 行け Don't get in my way じゃあね 黙って
Hey playboy, go away, don't get in my way. Bye now, quiet down
ワン ツー スリー ワン ツー スリー ワン ツー スリー
One, two, three, one, two, three, one, two, three
Sit down Sit down ワン ツー スリー ワン ツー スリー ワン ツー スリー
Sit down, sit down. One, two, three, one, two, three, one, two, three
まさかのバイバイ
An unexpected bye-bye
ワン ツー スリー ワン ツー スリー ワン ツー スリー
One, two, three, one, two, three, one, two, three
Sit down Sit down ワン ツー スリー... Sit down Sit down
Sit down, sit down. One, two, three... Sit down, sit down
特報！
[Special News!]
フルアニメーションMV
[Full Animation Music Video]
配信後 プレミア公開！
[Premiering After the Stream!]
MV公開に先駆けてー
[Ahead of the MV Release—]
ARE YOU READY?
痛くて 目を塞いでも 聞こえちゃう不安症
Even if I cover my eyes in pain, my anxiety still hears it all
悩んでも変わらないから なんだかんだやるしかないか
Worrying changes nothing, so I guess I just have to do it
壊れるならいっそ 直しやすいように どんな形 目指せるかな
If it breaks, it'll just be easier to fix. What kind of shape can I aim for?
助走なしのジャンプ 紐なしでダイブ 今日のあたし 褒めてあげたいじゃんか
Jumping without a running start, diving without a rope. Shouldn't I praise who I am today?
息したい もっと響きたい
I want to breathe, I want to resonate more
ねぇあたし以上が見れるかも 妄想止まんないや
Hey, maybe you'll see something even beyond me. My wild imagination won't stop
ファッションビート 嗅いでみちゃう？ 夢にあっそなんて 吐けやしないな
Fashion Beat—wanna take a whiff? I can't just scoff 'so what' at my dreams
叶えるのはあたし自身か それとも誰かにお任せか ただただ自分に勝ちたい
Will I fulfill them myself, or leave it to someone else? I just simply want to beat myself
ニュー ファッションビート 愛を喰らう 負けるなんてごめんだ 味覚がしないな
New Fashion Beat, consuming love. Losing is out of the question, it leaves a bad taste
何度でも灰になる進化 生まれ変わるバグの擬人化 まだまだ腐ってあげない そう、ない
Evolving into ash over and over, the personification of a reborn bug. I won't rot away just yet, no way
チクチク刺してくるのは 飽き飽きしてるわ
I'm sick and tired of these constant little stabs
ごめん 鬱陶しい 言葉遊びはどうかちゃんと仕舞っておいて
Sorry, but please keep your annoying wordplay to yourself
私こそがライバル 当たり前の解釈 どうしたらいい 分かってるのに
I am my own rival, an obvious truth. Even though I know what I should do
助走なしのジャンプ 紐なしでダイブ 今日のあたし 出来る気しないなって
Jumping without a running start, diving without a rope. Thinking I can't do it today...
気にしない なんて無理じゃない？
Isn't it impossible to just ignore it?
ねぇあたし以外と比べても クソつまんないじゃんか うぜぇーー
Hey, comparing yourself to anyone other than me is totally lame! So annoying!
ファッションビート 嗅いでみちゃう？
Fashion Beat—wanna take a whiff?
夢にあっそなんて吐けやしないな
I can't even tell you about my dreams.
叶えるのはあたし自身か
Will I make them come true myself,
それとも誰かにお任せか
or leave it to someone else?
ただただ自分に勝ちたい
I just want to overcome myself!
ニュー ファッションビート
New Fashion Beat!
愛を喰らう
Devouring love,
負けるなんてごめんだ味がないな
I refuse to lose—there's no taste in that.
何度でも灰になる進化 生まれ変わるバグの擬人化
Evolving into ashes again and again, a reborn personification of a bug.
まだまだ腐ってあげない そんなーい
I won't rot away just yet—no way!
止まれない
I can't stop!
誰かじゃないあたし自身だ
It's not someone else, it's me!
生まれ変わるバグの擬人化
A reborn personification of a bug.
まだまだ
Not yet, not yet,
散ってあげない そんなーい
I won't fade away just yet—no way!
みんなー ライブ見てくれてありがとー！
Everyone, thank you so much for watching the live stream!
これからは告知のお時間です！
Now, it's time for some announcements!
まずはこちら！
First up is this!
さくらみこ 誕生日記念2026 記念グッズです！
Sakura Miko Birthday Commemoration 2026 merch!
まずは1つ目、こちら！タラーン！
Here is the first item! Ta-da!
アクリルパネル！
Acrylic panel!
イラストレーターはおるだん先生に描き下ろしていただきました！
The artwork was drawn by Ordan-sensei!
テーマは「電脳世界のマスコット」... 「電脳世界のみこ」！
The theme is "Miko in the Cyber World"!
新衣装のミコを描き下ろしてもらいました！
Miko in her new outfit was illustrated!
オーロラ加工でキラキラのアクリルパネルとなっております！めっちゃ可愛い！
It's a shiny acrylic panel with aurora coating! It's so cute!
続いてはこちら！
Next up is this!
スマホスタンドフィギュアです！
Smartphone stand figure!
スマホが立てかけられるスタンド、そして新衣装のミコのフィギュア！
A stand to place your phone on, plus a figure of Miko in her new outfit!
めちゃくちゃ可愛くないですか？これ、たくさんこだわったのでね、
Isn't it super cute? I put a lot of care into designing this,
ぜひね、このスタンドにスマホを立てかけて、配信見てくれたら嬉しいです！
so I'd be really happy if you propped your phone on it to watch my streams!
続いてはこちら！
Next up is this!
ガジェットケース！
Gadget case!
新衣装にちなんで、ちょっとこういうね、あんまり出さないグッズも考えてみました！
Inspired by the new outfit, I thought of making a unique item we don't often release!
ケーブルとかね、モバイルバッテリーなど小物を収納できるケースとなっております！
It's a case to store small items like cables and power banks!
ソフトな素材になってるよ！
It's made of a soft material!
最後はこちら！
And finally, this!
ナイロンジャケット！
Nylon jacket!
新衣装をモチーフにしたナイロンジャケットとなっております！
It's a nylon jacket themed around my new outfit!
ちょっとかっこいいめのデザインなので、みんな一緒にお揃いになってくれたら嬉しいです！
It's got a cool design, so I'd love it if we could all match!
そして、フルセット購入特典はこちら！
And here is the Full Set Purchase Bonus!
さくらみこ直筆サイン&箔押し複製メッセージ入りおるだん描き下ろしポストカードとなっております！
A postcard illustrated by Ordan, with my handwritten signature and foil-stamped message!
ま、ちょっと数量限定にはなるんですが、みんなお早めによろしくお願いします！
Quantities are limited, so please check it out as soon as possible!
そして、通常版は、さくらみこ箔押し複製サイン&メッセージ入りのポストカードとなっております！
And the standard version comes with a foil-stamped printed signature and message postcard!
みんな、ぜひね、たくさん手に入れてくれると嬉しいです！よろしくお願いします！
Everyone, I'd be so happy if you could get your hands on it! Thank you!
そして、告知2つ目はこちら！
And now for the second announcement!
なんと！さくらみこ×学研さんの参考書シリーズが発売決定になりましたー！
Sakura Miko x Gakken study guide book series release has been confirmed!
ホロライブStudy Book『さくらみこでもわかる』シリーズとなっております！
It's the Hololive Study Book "Easy Enough Even for Sakura Miko" series!
中学漢字+語彙、中学数学、中学英単語、中学地理+都道府県の4冊が発売決定です！
Four books will be released: Junior High Kanji & Vocab, Math, English Vocab, and Geography!
そして、初回限定の愛蔵版も発売予定となっております！
Plus, a First-Press Limited Collector's Edition is scheduled for release!
4月下旬頃より予約開始なので、引き続き続報をチェックしてね！
Pre-orders start around late April, so keep an eye out for further details!
うーん、みんな説得力があると思うよね！
Hmm, I think everyone finds it pretty convincing, right?
次！
Next!
3つ目はこちら！
The third announcement is this!
さくらみこ×フレーベル館 初の絵本『みこぴーとおおきなさくらのき』が本日より発売です！
Sakura Miko x Froebel-kan first picture book "Mikopee and the Big Cherry Tree" is on sale today!
もう買ってくれた人もいるかな？
Has anyone bought it already?
いつも支えてくれている35Pを題材に夢だった絵本を作ることができました！
The picture book of my dreams, themed around 35P who always support me, is finally made!
全国の書店やローソンさんで購入可能なので、ぜひぜひみんな手に取ってください！よろしくお願いします！がんばりましたー！
It's available at bookstores and Lawson nationwide, so please check it out! I worked hard on it!
続いてはこちら！大発表！
Moving on to this! Big announcement!
4つ目はこちら！
The fourth announcement is this!
さくらみこ フィギュア化が決定しましたー！
Sakura Miko figure release has been confirmed!
おるだん先生監修にて、みこの夢だった等身大フィギュアがついに完成です！やったー！
Supervised by Ordan-sensei, my dream life-sized figure is finally complete! Yay!
スケールフィギュアも同時に予約販売が決まりました！
A scale figure pre-order sale has also been confirmed at the same time!
明日3月6日からの予約開始です！
Pre-orders open tomorrow, March 6th!
EXPOのDesign COCOさんブースで展示されるので、みんな見に来てね！たくさん写真撮ってね！
It will be on display at the Design COCO booth at EXPO, so come see it and take lots of photos!
また、この等身大フィギュアも展示される...
Also, where this life-sized figure will be displayed...
京都IP書店×さくらみこのポップアップショップも開催決定となりました！すごい！
Kyoto IP Bookstore x Sakura Miko Pop-Up Shop has been confirmed! Awesome!
リニューアルオープンした京都TSUTAYA IP書店...
At the newly reopened Kyoto TSUTAYA IP Bookstore...
4月28日から開催です！
Starting April 28th!
オリジナルグッズの販売やノベルティのコラボも行われるので
Original merchandise will be sold and novelty collabs will be held,
皆さん楽しみにしてください！
so please look forward to it, everyone!
もりだくさんだ～！
There's so much in store!
そして！まだございます！
And! There's even more!
続いてはこちら！
Next up is this!
さくらみこ×HYTE コラボPCケース発売決定！
Sakura Miko x HYTE collab PC case release confirmed!
キーキャップとデスクマットのセットもございます！
Keycap and desk mat sets are also available!
先行予約やニュース、メール通知や詳細については
For pre-orders, news, email notifications, and details,
hyte.ceo/miko を見てみてください！
please check out hyte.ceo/miko!
楽しみににしててねー！
Please look forward to it!
そして！
And!
今年もしゃくらみこ×鳴門鯛焼本舗さんのコラボが実施中です！
This year again, the Sakura Miko x Naruto Taiyaki Honpo collab is underway!
今年でなんと4回目です！ありがとうございます！
This is actually our 4th time! Thank you so much!
3月31日までなので
It runs until March 31st,
みんなぜひ食べに行ってください！
so everyone, please go try it!
続いて！
Next!
新曲「FASHIONBEAT」本日0時よりリリースです！
New song "FASHIONBEAT" will be released today at midnight!
MVはこのあとプレミア公開！みんな見てね！
The MV will premiere right after this! Everyone, check it out!
とっても豪華なアニメMVとなっております！よろしくお願いします！
It's a super lavish anime MV! Please look forward to it!
はい！そしてこちら！
Yes! And this!
明日からホロライブSUPER EXPO 7th fes.開催です！
Starting tomorrow, Hololive SUPER EXPO and 7th fes. are happening!
3日間の開催ですよ！すごい！
It's a 3-day event! Amazing!
みこはですね、7th fes.ではDay2のSTAGE2に参加します！みんな見に来てね！
Miko will participate in Stage 2 on Day 2 of 7th fes.! Come see me!
このあとはメンバー限定の撮影会もあるので、みんなみこPになってね！
After this, there's a member-limited photo session, so join Miko-P!
ということで、告知が盛り盛りの盛りになりましたが、みんなついてこられたかな？
So, with so many announcements packed in, was everyone able to keep up?
みこ、これからも頑張るのでよろしくお願いします！誕生日祝ってくれてありがとう！
Miko will keep working hard, so please support me! Thank you for celebrating my birthday!
おつみこー！
Otsumiko~!
生誕LIVE 2026♡ 今年も祝ってくれてありがとう！！
[Birthday LIVE 2026♡ Thank you for celebrating with me again this year!!]
みんなのおかげでたくさんのことを乗り越えてみこでいられてるよ。まだまだ笑っていこう！！
[Thanks to everyone, I've overcome so much to be Miko. Let's keep smiling!!]
そしてこれからもきらめき続けるあきらめない心で アイドルがんばる！！ さくらみこ 2026.3.5
[And I'll keep doing my best as an idol with a shining, never-give-up spirit!! - Sakura Miko 2026.3.5]
生誕LIVE 2026♡ 今年も祝ってくれてありがとう〜！！ みんなのおかげでたくさんのことを乗り越えて過ごせてるよ。まだまだ笑っていこう！！ そしてこれからも挑み続ける あきらめない心でアイドル頑張る！！ さくらみこ
[Birthday LIVE 2026♡ Thank you for celebrating with me again this year~! Thanks to everyone, I've overcome so much. Let's keep smiling! I'll keep trying my best as an idol with a never-give-up spirit!! - Sakura Miko]